She's a girl from the big city. He's a reckless soldier of fortune. For a fabulous
treasure, they share an adventure no one could imagine... or survive.
Romancing the Stone is a romance, comedy, action
film directed by Robert Zemeckis.
Though she can spin wild tales of passionate romance,
novelist Joan Wilder has no life of her own.
Then one day adventure comes her way in the form of a mysterious package.
It turns out that the parcel is the ransom she'll need to free her
abducted sister, so Joan flies to South America to hand it over.
But she gets on the wrong bus and winds up hopelessly stranded in the jungle.
Jack T. Colton, played by Michael Douglas.
Joan Wilder, played by Kathleen Turner.
Ralph, played by Danny DeVito.
Ira, played by Zack Norman.
Juan, played by Alfonso Arau.
Zolo, played by Manuel Ojeda.
Romancing the Stone is a 1984 romantic comedy-adventure film directed by Robert Zemeckis, written by Diane Thomas and
produced by Michael Douglas, who also stars in the film alongside Kathleen Turner and Danny DeVito.
The film follows a romance novelist who must venture beyond her New York City comfort zone to
Colombia to save her widowed sister from criminals who are holding her for ransom.
Thomas wrote the screenplay in 1979.
Zemeckis, who at the time was developing Cocoon, liked Thomas's screenplay and offered to direct but 20th Century Fox
initially declined, citing the commercial failure of his first two films I Wanna Hold Your Hand and Used Cars.
Zemeckis was eventually dismissed from Cocoon after an early screening of
Romancing the Stone failed to impress studio executives further.
Alan Silvestri, who would collaborate with Zemeckis on
his later films, composed the score.
Romancing the Stone was released on March 30, 1984, to positive reviews from
critics and earned over $115 million worldwide at the box office.
A sequel, The Jewel of the Nile, was released one year and
nine months later on December 11, 1985.
The film explores themes of airplane, smuggling
(contraband), chase, kidnapping, crocodile.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.